A Guide to the Alice Lee Stringfellow Shultice papers, 1916-1950
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Alice Lee Stringfellow Shultice papers, 1916-1950
The Library of Virginia
51389
.45 cu. ft. and 1 box
Alice Lee Stringfellow Shultice
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
Alice Lee Stringfellow was born 27 November 1871 in Alexandria, Virginia, to Frank Stringfellow and Emmas Green Stringfellow. She married Robert William Shultice (1867-1943) 23 January 1896 and they had two children. The couple lived in Norfolk, Virginia, where Robert Shultice was an attorney and postmaster. Alice Shultice was active in women's organizations and in genealogical organizations. She also was appointed to various Virginia state government commissions. Alice Lee Stringfellow Shultice died 24 August 1964 in Norfolk, Virginia, and was buried in Elmwood Cemetery in Norfolk.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1916-1950, of Alice Lee Stringfellow Shultice (1871-1964) of Norfolk, Virginia, consisting of birthday cards, clippings, correspondence, essays, guest cards, invitations, maps, pamphlets, programs, receipts, and other papers detailing her work with various civic and social organizations, including Virginia state commissions, Norfolk civic committees, women's organizations, and genealogical societies, as well as government and private organizations assisting with the war efforts during World War I and World War II. Papers also include correspondence from friends containing social and personal news.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1916-1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1932-1933, 1937, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- American Committee for Devastated France, 1918-1921 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- American Foundation for the Blind, Inc., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- American Red Cross, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Assembly of Tidewater Virginia Women, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities, 1923, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Colonial Dames, 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Daughters of the American Colonists, Pocahontas Chapter, 1940, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Daughters of the American Revolution, 1944-1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Daughters of Colonial Wars, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Order of First Families of Virginia, 1944, 1948-1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Institute of American Genealogy, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- National League for Woman's Service, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- National Surgical Dressing Committee, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- City of Norfolk, 1919, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Norfolk Advertising Board, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Pilot International, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Travelers' Aid Society, 1919, 1933, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- United Service Organizations (USO), 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- University of Virginia Institute of Public Affairs, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Virginia Commission for the Blind, 1932, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Appointment to the Board of Charities and Corrections, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Appointment as delegate to the 51st Congress of the American Prison Association, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Virginia Historical Society, 1926, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Virginia School for the Deaf and the Blind, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Virginia War History Commission, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Young Men's Christian Association and Young Women's Christian Association, 1919, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Papers, 1925, 1939, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Clippings, 1931, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Clippings, 1941, 1947, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Clippings, 1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)